<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Studies on Praxis</title>
    <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Studies on Praxis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://praxis.nyc/study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Radical Care</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/radical-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/radical-care/</guid>
      <description> Corruption of care TBD Neoliberalism – the ideology at the root of all our problems (article) From Managerial Feudalism to the Revolt of the Caring Classes (video, 59:10)    Ideologies on Care TBD Cindy Milstein on grief, mourning, and building institutions for care in anarchist movements (podcast)  Silvia Federici - On Elder Care Work And The Limits of Marxism  (19 pages) The Care Manifesto chapter 2, Caring Kinships    Institutional Care TBD Information Maintenance As a Practice of Care Hail The Maintainers (article)    Pirate Care (guest speakers) TBD Introduction to Pirate Care  Criminalization of Solidarity  The Hologram: a peer-to-peer social technology of care   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panopticon</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/panopticon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/panopticon/</guid>
      <description>Discussing Shoshana Zuboff&#39;s The Age of Surveillance Capitalism. We highly suggest you to listen to Shoshana&#39;s talk at Data &amp; Society (1:08 total, start at 5min).
  Panopticon session 1 Initial Talk Thursday 7/18/2018, 7 to 9pm Private space Relevant links (from our signal group):  QR is King Mobile technology is increasingly serving as the vehicle for a sophisticated national surveillance system that’s deeply intertwined with all kinds of necessary everyday transactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>enslavement</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/enslavement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/enslavement/</guid>
      <description>Debt By David Graeber Jan 16th 2021 - 2pm EST chapter 6 - Games With Sex and Death Download PDF get calendar invite visit room    Slavery and Social Death By Orlando Patterson Feb 13 2021 - 2pm EST Chapter 2 - Authority, Alienation, and Social Death Download PDF get calendar invite visit room    Scenes of Subjection By Saidiya Hartman Mar 6th 2021 - 2pm EST Chapter 2 - Redressing the Pained Body: Toward a Theory of Practice Download PDF get calendar invite visit room    Against The Grain By James C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bureaucracy</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/bureaucracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 02:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/bureaucracy/</guid>
      <description>the visible hand Thursday, August 6, 2020, 6-8PM EST  get calendar invite visit room 1. The Visible Hand: The Ascendancy of the Manager (Page 504 - 511 via absolute PDF pages or 490 - 497 via printed pages) Download PDF 2. From Managerial Feudalism to the Revolt of the Caring Classes - David Graeber at CCC (59:10) Watch Video    anarchist cybernetics Thursday, August 20, 2020, 6-8PM EST  get calendar invite visit room 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collapsism</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/collapsism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 02:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/collapsism/</guid>
      <description>compos mentis Tuesday, March 31, 2020, 7:30-9:30PM EST  get calendar invite online: visit room 1. systemic risks to civilization and responses (45 min)   2. Life Through A Polyvagal Lens (1h 20 min, start 5min in)  other media (audio, etc)    map making Thursday, April 9, 2020, 7:30-9:30PM EST  get calendar invite online: visit room 1. The Mushroom at the End of the World (Prologue, 9 pages) Download PDF 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperreal</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/hyperreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/hyperreal/</guid>
      <description>This study circle met in Brooklyn every other Wednesday starting April 18 2018 for a total of five sessions.
  Dude, You Broke the Future Wednesday 4/18/2018, 7 to 9pm at June Bar Dude, You Broke the Future video, 57 minutes Simulacra and Simulation The Precession of Simulacra, page 3 The Divine Irreference of Images, page 4   Download PDF     Society of Spectacle Wednesday 5/2/2018, 7 to 9pm at 375 Menahan Street Chapter 1: The Culmination of Separation Chapter 2: The Commodity as Spectacle Chapter 6: Spetacular Time   download PDF    The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction Wednesday 5/16/2018, 7 to 9pm at 375 Menahan Street Download PDF    Understanding Media Wednesday 6/6/2018, 7 to 9pm at June Bar The Gadget Lover: Narcissus as Narcosis Challenge and Collapse: The Nemesis of Creativity Download PDF    Immediatism, Hakim Bey Wednesday 7/19/2018, 7 to 9pm at Tradesman Bar Immediatism chapter (page 12) Download PDF Telekommunist Manifesto The Manifesto of the Telekommunisten Network Download PDF Simulacra and Simulation  Hypermarket and Hypercommodity, page 52 The Implosion of Meaning in the Media, page 55 Simulacra and science fiction, page 81   download PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nomadism</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/nomadism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/nomadism/</guid>
      <description>This study circle met in Brooklyn every other week starting March 5th 2019 for a total of four sessions.
  Treatise on Nomadology: The War Machine Tuesday, Mar 5th 2019, 7-9pm A Thousand Plateaus Deleuze and Guattari  Download PDF    Apparatus of Capture Tuesday, March 19 2019, 7-9pm A Thousand Plateaus Deleuze and Guattari  Download PDF   --  The Smooth and the Striated Tuesday, March 26 2019, 7-9pm A Thousand Plateaus Deleuze and Guattari  Download PDF    Thin Simplifications and Practical Knowledge: Metis Tuesday, April 9 2019, 7-9pm Seeing Like a State James C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queer Families</title>
      <link>https://praxis.nyc/study/queer-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 18:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praxis.nyc/study/queer-families/</guid>
      <description> The Dialect of Sex: The Case for a Feminist Revolution by Shulamith Firestone Thursday August 10th 2017, 7-9pm Bluestockings Bookstore Chapter 1 download PDF    The Straight Mind and Other Essays by Monique Wittig Thursday August 24th 2017, 7-9pm June Bar One Is Not Born a Woman Download PDF The Straight Mind  On the Social Contract   Download PDF     Feminism is Queer: The Intimate Connection Between Queer and Feminist Theory by Mimi Marinucci  Wednesday September 13th 2017, 7-9pm  June Bar chapter TBD download PDF    The History of Sexuality by Michel Foucault Wednesday September 27th 2017, 7-9pm June Bar chapter TBD Download PDF    The Dialect of Sex: The Case for a Feminist Revolution by Shulamith Firestone Thursday October 25th 2017, 7-9pm June Bar Last chapter download PDF  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
